Kuntal Trivedi CSM® LSSGB

Gandhinagar, Gujarat | kuntaltrivedi1993@gmail.com | +919173125715 | linkedin.com/in/kuntal-trivedi

SUMMARY

A skilled professional, solution-oriented Project Manager/Business Analyst with 6+ years of experience in elicitation, management and documentation of business requirements using industry standard process and methodology for IT projects across a wide variety of domains and technologies.

SKILLS

Artifacts Designed

- Functional Requirements Document (FRD)
- Business Requirements Document (BRD)
- Business Approach
 Document
- User Stories
- Flow Diagrams
- Wireframes
- Scope of Work (SOW)
- Use Cases
- Feature List Document
- User Manuals

Interpersonal & Consultative

- Quality reporting
- Communicator
- Decision maker
- Problem solver
- Ability to lead/mentor
- Team management

Software Tools

- Jira
- Balsamiq
- Visio
- Basecamp
- Zoho Projects
- eMAnager

EXPERIENCE

Softweb Solutions Pvt. Ltd.-an Avnet Company | Business Analyst

May 2021-Till Date

- My Skill Set includes but not limited to Business Analysis, Process Management and Project Management.
- Interfaced with cross-functional team, including developers, software architects and services, to propose system solutions.
- Assists with User Interface Design and modelling UI wireframes.
- Worked with a wide range of enterprise customers, Fortune 500 companies, and start-up companies across different geographies.
- Primary functional liaison throughout the software development lifecycle with the technology team.
- Experienced working with Agile/Scrum through writing user stories & acceptance criteria and Waterfall SDLC models.
- Good experience in working with projects involving latest technologies such as IoT, AI, AR/VR & MR and ML.
- Participation in daily Scrums, Sprint meeting and Sprint review meeting to keep a track on ongoing development and workout the way in order to eliminate roadblocks and enhance productivity.
- Excellent communication and collaboration skills with ability to speak knowledgeably with members of both the business and technical teams.

- Strong problem solving and structuring skills, with ability to bring actionable insights through effective communication.
- Working closely with the enterprise clients to understand the project scope and translate that into a business requirement for the technical team.
- Demonstrated exceptional skills of project management while keeping the stakeholders involved at all stages, thereby increasing customer loyalty, retention and generating repeat business.
- Experienced in creating various documents such as Functional Requirements Document (FRD), Scope of work document, Project approach document, User stories with acceptance criteria, Use cases, User acceptance testing (UAT) sheet, Product backlog sheet and User manuals.

eClinicalWorks India Pvt. Ltd. | Project Manager

Dec 2016- May 2021

- Manage day-to-day operational aspects of a project and scope.
- Own multiple accounts from activation until project closure.
- Review deliverables prepared by team before passing to client.
- Effectively apply Agile and Waterfall methodology and enforces project standards.
- Ensure that the project documents are complete, current, and stored appropriately.
- Facilitate team and client meetings effectively.
- Hold regular status meetings with project team.
- Resolve and/or escalates issues in a timely fashion.
- Worked on projects having cloud environment setup or SaaS setup.
- Administer, configure, upgrade, and troubleshoot Tomcat application servers and fax servers in SAAS as well as client server environment.
- Handles organizations hardware related concerns. Guides on the server requirements and how to manage them.
- Develop lasting relationships with client personnel that foster client ties.
- Continually seek opportunities to increase customer satisfaction and deepen client relationships.
- Understand customer limitations and propose alternatives / workarounds.
- Execute the SOP (Scope of project) in proper manner.
- Working with Developers in case any Bug has been found while performing Testing.

eSec Security Consultants Pvt. Ltd | Assistant Project Manager

Aug 2015-Dec 2016

• Worked in a WIRELESS SURAKSHA SETU IP CCTV SURVEILLANCE project, for Government of GUJARAT POLICE, In which I have given a duty to maintain the entire network system and server to make sure efficient performance of CCTV cameras. Also, I have to make Network of wireless devices to gain optimum output in the form of signal to run the system smoothly. As a part of duty, I have to perform several tasks including installation and configuration of CCTV camera and wireless device like NANO STATION M5, NANO BEAM M5, AIRGRID M5(all these products are from UBIQUITI NETWORKS) and NUUO NVR (NETWORK VIDEO RECORDER) surveillance system. Apart from this I have to manage a team of 10 Engineers and guide them to different zones of multiple cities of Gujarat to carryout maximum output and provide remote support.

EDUCATION

Shankersinh Vaghela Bapu Institute Of Technology | B.E (EC)

Gandhinagar | **2011-2015**

• Final year project was under Microsoft Company and achieved certification from Microsoft Partner.

Extra-Curricular Activities

- Attended Texas Instruments Innovation Challenge India Analog Design Contest.
- Attended workshop on Sixth Sense
- Got 2nd rank in Model making competition held by GTU S4 club in SVBIT college.
- Got 1st rank in Dance in cultural festival of college.
- Participated in various competition/activities like Dance, Robotics Techfest, Cricket
- Coordinator in BAJA SAE India 2014 event which is the national level Technical Racing event
- GTU S4(Student Startup Support System) club Coordinator
- Coordinator in Blood donation camp by Indian Red Cross Society
- Organized workshop on Arduino board at my college
- Event coordinator of National Level Techfest entitled as TEKVIDEN in my college

CERTIFICATION

Certified Scrum Master
Scrum AllianceLean Six Sigma Green
Belt
ASCB(E)- Accreditation
Service for Certifying
Bodies (Europe) LtdBusiness Analysis
Fundamentals
UdemyFundamentals of IOT
Udemy

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Got an award of a "Promising Performer 2016" by Esec Security Consultants Pvt Ltd.
- Received an award of a "Rising Star 2017" by eClinicalWorks India Pvt Ltd.
- Received multiple appreciation from enterprise clients and company management